[{
	"id": 0,
    "question": "A PHP script should start with ___ and end with ___.",
    "a": "< php >",
    "b": "< ? php ?>",
    "c": "<? ?>",
    "d": "<?php ?>",
    "answer": "<? ?>"
},
{
	"id": 1,
    "question": "A function in PHP which starts with __ (double underscore) is know as..",
    "a": "Magic Function",
    "b": "Inbuilt Function",
    "c": "Default Function",
    "d": "User Defined Function",
    "answer": "Magic Function"
},
{
	"id": 2,
    "question": "Which one of the following can be used to instantiate an object in PHP assuming class name to be Foo?",
    "a": "$obj = new $foo;",
    "b": "$obj = new foo;",
    "c": "$obj = new foo ();",
    "d": "obj = new foo ();",
    "answer": "$obj = new foo ();"
},
{
	"id": 3,
    "question": "Which one of the following is the right description for the method getMessage() ?",
    "a": "Returns the message if it is passed to the constructor",
    "b": "Returns the message if it is passed to the class",
    "c": "Returns the message if it is passed to the file",
    "d": "Returns the message if it is passed to the object",
    "answer": "Returns the message if it is passed to the constructor"
},
{
	"id": 4,
    "question": "Which one of the following regular expression matches any string containing zero or one p?",
    "a": "p+",
    "b": "p*",
    "c": "P?",
    "d": "p#",
    "answer": "P?"
},
{
	"id": 5,
    "question": "Which one of the following methods is responsible for sending the query to the database?",
    "a": "query()",
    "b": "send_query()",
    "c": "sendquery()",
    "d": "query_send()",
    "answer": "query()"
},
{
	"id": 6,
    "question": "Which one of the following function is capable of reading a file into an array?",
    "a": "file()",
    "b": "arrfile()",
    "c": "arr_file()",
    "d": "file_arr()",
    "answer": "file()"
},
{
	"id": 7,
    "question": "What will be the output of the following PHP code ?\n<?php\n$x = 4;\n$y = 3;\n$z = 1;\necho \"$x = $x + $y + $z\";\n?>",
    "a": "4 = 4 + 3 + 1",
    "b": "8",
    "c": "8 = 4 + 3 +1",
    "d": "Error",
    "answer": "4 = 4 + 3 + 1"
},
{
	"id": 8,
    "question": "What will be the output of the following PHP code ?\n<?php\nswitch($b)\n{\ncase 2:\n    print \"hello\";\n    break;\ncase b:\n    print \"hi\";\n    break;\n}\n?>",
    "a": "hello",
    "b": "hi",
    "c": "no output",
    "d": "error",
    "answer": "no output"
},
{
	"id": 9,
    "question": "Which of the following advanced OOP features is/are not supported by PHP?",
    "a": "Method overloading",
    "b": "Multiple Inheritance",
    "c": "a and b both",
    "d": "Object Cloning",
    "answer": "a and b both"
},
{
	"id": 10,
    "question": "Which of the conditional statements is/are supported by PHP?",
    "a": "switch statements",
    "b": "if statements",
    "c": "if-else statements",
    "d": "All of the mentioned",
    "answer": "d"
},
{
	"id": 11,
    "question": "What will be the output of the following PHP code?\n<?php\n$a = array(\"red\", \"green\", \"blue\");\narray_pop($a);\nprint_r($a);\n?>",
    "a": "Array([0] => red [1] => green)",
    "b": "Array([0] => green [1] => blue)",
    "c": "Array([0] => red [1] => blue)",
    "d": "Array([0] => blue [1] => blue)",
    "answer": "Array([0] => red [1] => green)"
},
{
	"id": 12,
    "question": "Which one of the following keyword is used to inherit our subclass into a superclass?",
    "a": "extends",
    "b": "implements",
    "c": "inherit",
    "d": "include",
    "answer": "extends"
},
{
	"id": 13,
    "question": "Which of the following is/are an external data?\ni) Cookies\nii) Input data from a form\niii) Server Variables\niv) Web services data",
    "a": "Only ii)",
    "b": "ii) and iii)",
    "c": "None of the mentioned",
    "d": "All of the mentioned",
    "answer": "All of the mentioned"
},
{
	"id": 14,
    "question": "Which one of the following functions finds the last occurrence of a string, returning its numerical position?",
    "a": "strlastpos()",
    "b": "strpos()",
    "c": "strlast()",
    "d": "strrpos()",
    "answer": "strrpos()"
},
{
	"id": 15,
    "question": "Which one of the following function is used to start a session?",
    "a": "start_session()",
    "b": "session_start()",
    "c": "session_begin()",
    "d": "begin_session()",
    "answer": "session_start()"
},
{
	"id": 16,
    "question": "Which keyword precedes a method name?",
    "a": "method",
    "b": "function",
    "c": "public",
    "d": "protected",
    "answer": "function"
},
{
	"id": 17,
    "question": "PHP has long supported two regular expression implementations known as _______ and _______.\ni) Perl\nii) PEAR\niii) Pearl\niv) POSIX",
    "a": "i) and ii)",
    "b": "ii) and iv)",
    "c": "i) and iv)",
    "d": "ii) and iii)",
    "answer": "i) and iv)"
},
{
	"id": 18,
    "question": "What will be the output of the following PHP code?\n<?php\n    function sum($num1, $num2)\n    {\n        $total = $num1 + $num2;\n        echo \"cos($total)\"; \n    }\n    sum(5,-5);    \n?>",
    "a": "0",
    "b": "1",
    "c": "0.5",
    "d": "-0.5",
    "answer": "1"
},
{
	"id": 19,
    "question": "How many functions does PHP offer for searching strings using POSIX style regular expression?",
    "a": "7",
    "b": "8",
    "c": "9",
    "d": "10",
    "answer": "7"
},
{
	"id": 20,
    "question": "Which of the following method acts as a destructor function in a PHP class?",
    "a": "class_name()",
    "b": "__destruct",
    "c": "destructor",
    "d": "None of the above.",
    "answer": "__destruct"
},
{
	"id": 21,
    "question": "Which of the following provides access to the uploaded file in the temporary directory on the web server?",
    "a": "$_FILES['file']['tmp_name']",
    "b": "$_FILES['file']['name']",
    "c": "$_FILES['file']['size']",
    "d": " $_FILES['file']['type']",
    "answer": "$_FILES['file']['tmp_name']"
},
{
	"id": 22,
    "question": "Which of the following is true about php variables?",
    "a": "Variables can, but do not need, to be declared before assignment.",
    "b": "Variables in PHP do not have intrinsic types - a variable does not know in advance whether it will be used to store a number or a string of characters.",
    "c": "Variables used before they are assigned have default values.",
    "d": "All of the above.",
    "answer": "All of the above."
},
{
	"id": 23,
    "question": "Who is the father of PHP?",
    "a": "Rasmus Lerdorf",
    "b": "Willam Makepiece",
    "c": "Drek Kolkevi",
    "d": "List Barely",
    "answer": "Rasmus Lerdorf"
},
{
	"id": 24,
    "question": "Which one of the following PHP functions can be used to find files?",
    "a": "glob()",
    "b": "file()",
    "c": "fold()",
    "d": "get_file()",
    "answer": "glob()"
},
{
	"id": 25,
    "question": "The practice of separating the user from the true inner workings of an application through well-known interfaces is known as _________",
    "a": "Polymorphism",
    "b": "Inheritance",
    "c": "Encapsulation",
    "d": "Abstraction",
    "answer": "Encapsulation"
},
{
	"id": 26,
    "question": "Which of the following statements causes PHP to disregard repeated error messages that occur within the same file and on the same line?",
    "a": "ignore_repeated_errors",
    "b": "ignore_repeat_error",
    "c": "repeatedly_ignore_error",
    "d": "repeated_error_ignore",
    "answer": "ignore_repeated_errors"
},
{
	"id": 27,
    "question": "Which variable is used to collect form data sent with both the GET and POST methods?",
    "a": "$BOTH",
    "b": "$_BOTH",
    "c": "$REQUEST",
    "d": "$_REQUEST",
    "answer": "$_REQUEST"
},
{
	"id": 28,
    "question": "What will be the output of the following PHP code ?\n<?php\nfunction fun()\n{\n    $x = 0;\n    echo $x;\n    $x++;\n}\nfun();\nfun();\nfun();\n?>",
    "a": "012",
    "b": "123",
    "c": "000",
    "d": "111",
    "answer": "000"
},
{
	"id": 29,
    "question": "__clone() is run on the ___ object.",
    "a": "original",
    "b": "pseudo",
    "c": "external",
    "d": "copied",
    "answer": "copied"
}]